Guide to the Washington Square Park (New York, N.Y.) and Washington Square Area Image Collection, 1850-1990 NYU_ARCH_PHOTO_00001
New York University Archives
Washington Square Park (New York, N.Y.), Washington Square Area, and Campus Buildings Image Collection
1850-1990
NYU_ARCH_PHOTO_00001
New York University Archives
7.5 linear feet
This collection contains images of Washington Square Park (New York, N.Y.), the Washington Square area (below 14th Street, above Houston St.) and the old University Building from the New York University Archives image collection.
New York University.
Digital Pilot Project
This finding aid is the result of the New York University Bobst Library's Digital Pilot Project, a case study in special collections digitization, undertaken as a collaboration between the University Archives, The Barbara Goldsmith Preservation and Conservation Department, and Digital Library Technical Services, with the support of the developers of The Archivists' Toolkit. The goals of the project were to create a Washington Square Image website for the UA that integrated high quality digital images into an item-level EAD finding aid; to train the UA staff in preservation scanning and metadata creation, and to create guides for these processes that can be used for future projects.
Primary project support was provided by David O'Neill, Melitte Buchman, Brian Hoffman, Nancy Cricco and Paula DeStefano. Scanning and metadata creation for the Digital Pilot Project by David O'Neill, Peter Asch, Janet Bunde, Lisa Darms, Steven D'Avria, Annie Grunow, William McKeldin, Alex Starace and Laura Zeccardi.
Arrangement
The photographs in Series I and II are arranged chronologically and by subject. The photographs in Series III are arranged by type of view. Exterior views are arranged chronologically. Interior views are arranged by subject (type of room).
The files are grouped into three series:
I, Washington Square Park (New York, N.Y.)
II, Washington Square Area
III, Campus Building: University Building
Provenance
The photographs in the Washington Square Park and Washington Square Image Collection represent two series of the University Archives' larger Photography Collection. The Photography Collection consists of photographs that were separated from university administrative collections or received as part of regular accessions from the University Photo Bureau. The Photo Bureau was founded in 1952, and archived their own collections until the mid-1980s, when they began regularly transferring prints, contact sheets and negatives to the University archives. All prints received from the Photo Bureau and those separated from administrative collections were incoporated into existing subject-based series. The Washington Square Park and Washington Square Area series represent the subject categories selected by the University Archives for digitization in the Spring of 2008.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains images of Washington Square Park (New York, N.Y.), the Washington Square area (below 14th Street, above Houston St.) and the old University Building (1832-1894) from the New York University Archives photography collection. Almost all of the images are black and white gelatin silver prints, although a few are Polaroid photographs, color c-prints, or drawings. A number of the photographs are prints made from copy-negatives of original photographs, drawings or art prints. Many of the photographs were created by the New York University's Photo Bureau to document the University's geography and cultural life, and they provide evidence of the history of the Park and the surrounding area from the early 1800s through the 1990s. Series I and II include thumbnails that link to larger images. Series III is a recent addition. Images for Series III will be included in early 2012.
Related Material at the New York University Archives
Guide to the Records of the Washington Square Association, Inc. 1908-1979
Historical Note
The bulk of this collection contains photographic and print images of Washington Square Park and the surrounding area. Buildings that are part of New York University's Washington Square campus, extant as well as demolished are included in this collection.
There is a separate series for the the University Building, New York University's first permanent home. It was constructed on the northeast corner of the park between Washington Place and Waverly Place in 1833-34. Architects Ithiel Town, Alexander Jackson Davis, and James Dakin as well as NYU engineering professor David B. Douglass designed the university’s first building in the Gothic Revival-style. This type of architectural style was meant to evoke the medieval buildings of Oxford and Cambridge and link the more modern and practical American curriculum the university was founded on to the long, rich tradition of English education.
Initially, the building was too large for the student body to fill so residential rooms, studios, and laboratories were rented out to a variety of artists and inventors including Winslow Homer and Samuel F.B. Morse. In the late 19th century as the university expanded, the undergraduate college moved to the more spacious University Heights campus in the Bronx initially leading to the decline of the Washington Square campus and in 1894 the University Building was demolished. It was replaced by Main Building (now the Silver Center).
Sources:
"The University Building." The University Quarterly 17 (May 1894): 116-123. "University Building." New York University Education Quarterly (Spring 1981): 20.
Aerial photographs.; Greenwich Village (New York, N.Y.); New York University |x Buildings.; Photographs.; Washington Square Park (New York, N.Y.); Washington Square |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Series I: Washington Square Park (New York, N.Y.)
  Scope and Content Note
  This series contains photographs and prints of Washington Square Park as well as the structures surrounding the four sides of the Park.
  - Subseries A: Aerial Views
    - Aerial Views, 1890s, 1890-1899, 2001, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1907; wsp_av_1_1_01; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 1)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking South, circa 1890; wsp_av_1_1_02; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 2)
        Washington Square Park (New York, N.Y.)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking North, circa 1890; wsp_av_1_1_03; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 3)
    - Aerial Views, 1900-1919 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1919; wsp_av_1_2_01; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Sihler, Henry J. (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 1)
    - Aerial Views, 1920s, 1920-1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1926; wsp_av_1_3_01; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Sihler, Henry J. (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 1)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1913; wsp_av_1_3_02; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Sihler, Henry J. (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 2)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking East, circa 1920; wsp_av_1_3_03; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 3)
      - Washington Square Park Aerial View, circa 1926; wsp_av_1_3_04; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Sihler, Henry J. (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 4)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking East, circa 1926; wsp_av_1_3_05; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 5)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking East, circa 1926; wsp_av_1_3_06; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 6)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking West, 1926; wsp_av_1_3_07; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 7)
      - Washington Square Park Aerial View, 1926; wsp_av_1_3_08; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 8)
    - Aerial Views, 1930s, 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking North, circa 1930-1939; wsp_av_1_4_01; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 1)
      - Manhattan Skyline and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1934; wsp_av_1_4_02; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 2)
      - Manhattan Skyline and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1939; wsp_av_1_4_03; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 3)
      - Manhattan Skyline and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1930-1939; wsp_av_1_4_04; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 4)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1937; wsp_av_1_4_05; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 5)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1938; wsp_av_1_4_06; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Sozio, A.F. (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 6)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1938; wsp_av_1_4_07; black-and-white print (photograph), 4 x 6 inches; Sozio, A.F. (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 7)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1938; wsp_av_1_4_08; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 8)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1938; wsp_av_1_4_09; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 9)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1938; wsp_av_1_4_10; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Jackson, Edward E. (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 10)
    - Aerial Views, 1940s, 1940-1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking South, circa 1940-1949; wsp_av_1_5_01; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 1)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1947; wsp_av_1_5_02; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 2)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking East, circa 1940-1949; wsp_av_1_5_03; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 3)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1940; wsp_av_1_5_04; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 4)
        Greenwich Village (New York, N.Y.); Washington Square Park (New York, N.Y.)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1943; wsp_av_1_5_05; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 5)
      - Washington Square Area, Aerial View, 1947; wsp_av_1_5_06; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 6)
        Aerial photographs.
    - Aerial Views, 1946-50, 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1946; wsp_av_1_6_01; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 1)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1946-1950; wsp_av_1_6_02; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 2)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1946-1950; wsp_av_1_6_03; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 3)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1947; wsp_av_1_6_04; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 4)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking South, 1949; wsp_av_1_6_05; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 5)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1946; wsp_av_1_6_06; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Mal Gurian Associates. (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 6)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking West, circa 1946-1950; wsp_av_1_6_07; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Mal Gurian Associates. (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 7)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1946-1950; wsp_av_1_6_08; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 8)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1950; wsp_av_1_6_09; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 7 inches; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 9)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1946-1950; wsp_av_1_6_10; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Mal Gurian Associates. (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 10)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1949; wsp_av_1_6_11; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 11)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1946-1950; wsp_av_1_6_12; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 12)
    - Aerial Views, 1950s, 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Washington Square Park Aerial View, wsp_av_1_7_01; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 1)
      - Manhattan Skyline and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, wsp_av_1_7_02; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 2)
      - Manhattan Skyline and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1953; wsp_av_1_7_03; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 3)
      - Winter Scene, Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1950-1959; wsp_av_1_7_04; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 4)
      - Winter Scene, Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1950; wsp_av_1_7_05; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 5)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1953; wsp_av_1_7_06; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 6)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1950-1959; wsp_av_1_7_07; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 7)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1954; wsp_av_1_7_08; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Simmons, William (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 8)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1959; wsp_av_1_7_09; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Simmons, William (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 9)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1953; wsp_av_1_7_10; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 10)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1954; wsp_av_1_7_11; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Simmons, William (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 11)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, wsp_av_1_7_12; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Simmons, William (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 12)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1954; wsp_av_1_7_13; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Simmons, William (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 13)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1952; wsp_av_1_7_14; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 14)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1952; wsp_av_1_7_15; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 15)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1952; wsp_av_1_7_16; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 16)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1952; wsp_av_1_7_17; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 17)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1952; wsp_av_1_7_18; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 18)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking North, circa 1950; wsp_av_1_7_19; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Mal Gurian Associates. (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 19)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1950; wsp_av_1_7_20; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 20)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, wsp_av_1_7_21; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Mal Gurian Associates. (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 21)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1952; wsp_av_1_7_22; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 22)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking West, 1951; wsp_av_1_7_23; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 23)
    - Aerial Views, 1960s (Folder 1 of 2), 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1960; wsp_av_1_8_01; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Fairchild Aerial Surveys, inc.. (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 1)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, wsp_av_1_8_02; black-and-white print (photograph), 11 x 14 inches (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 2)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1965; wsp_av_1_8_03; black-and-white print (photograph), 11 x 14 inches (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 3)
      - Cars, Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1960-1969; wsp_av_1_8_04; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 4)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1960-1969; wsp_av_1_8_05; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Thomas Airviews. (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 5)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1960-1969; wsp_av_1_8_06; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 6)
      - Washington Square Area, Aerial View, Looking South, 1964; wsp_av_1_8_07; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Simmons, William (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 7)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1960-1969; wsp_av_1_8_08; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Thomas Airviews. (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 8)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1965; wsp_av_1_8_09; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Thomas Airviews. (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 9)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1968; wsp_av_1_8_10; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Thomas Airviews. (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 10)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1960-1969; wsp_av_1_8_11; black-and-white print (photograph), 11 x 14 inches (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 11)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking North, circa 1960-1969; wsp_av_1_8_12; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Giese, Al (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 12)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1963; wsp_av_1_8_13; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 13)
      - Manhattan Skyline and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1964; wsp_av_1_8_14; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Seligson, Stanley (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 14)
    - Aerial Views, 1960s (Folder 2 of 2), 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking North, circa 1960-1969; wsp_av_2_1_01; black-and-white print (photograph), 4 x 4 inches (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 1)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1968; wsp_av_2_1_02; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Thomas Airviews. (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 2)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1968; wsp_av_2_1_03; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Thomas Airviews. (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 3)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1968; wsp_av_2_1_04; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Thomas Airviews. (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 4)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1969; wsp_av_2_1_05; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Skyviews Survey, Inc.. (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 5)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1966; wsp_av_2_1_06; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Thomas Airviews. (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 6)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1960-1969; wsp_av_2_1_07; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Thomas Airviews. (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 7)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1960-1969; wsp_av_2_1_08; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Litton Industries. Aero Service Corporation. (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 8)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1969; wsp_av_2_1_09; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Skyviews Survey, Inc.. (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 9)
      - Manhattan Skyline and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, 1964; wsp_av_2_1_10; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches; Seligson, Stanley (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 10)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1960's; wsp_av_2_1_11; Pellettieri, Luigi (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 11)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, wsp_av_2_1_12; Mal Gurian Associates. (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 12)
      - New York University Buildings, Washington Square Area, Aerial View, 1967; wsp_av_2_1_13; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 13)
        Aerial photographs.; Washington Square Park (New York, N.Y.)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking North, circa 1960-1969; wsp_av_2_1_14; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 14)
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, Looking North, 1963; wsp_av_2_1_15; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 15)
        Aerial photographs.; Washington Square |z New York (State) |z New York.
      - Washington Square Area and Washington Square Park, Aerial View, circa 1960-1969; wsp_av_2_1_16; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 16)
      - Washington Square Park, Looking Southwest, circa 1967; wsp_av_2_1_17; color print (photograph), 3 x 5 inches (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 17)